S M SAMFFR

Data Specialist



SUMMARY

Software Engineer with around **1+ years** of experience in building user interactive applications, possess hands-on experience in solving syntactical challenges and scalability problems for different domains. Inclined towards the field of data engineering with a desire to expand my skill sets.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Specialist

Futurense Technologies 12/2022 - Ongoing Bangalore, Karnataka **Tools:** SQL, Python, Git, AWS Cloud, Hive, Hadoop

- Implemented SQL reporting on employee management system to gain insights on building various reporting formats
- Gained an overview of the whole process of Data Engineering
- Worked on core services in Azure Cloud under security, compute, storage, database, etc

Automation Engineer

Valenta Al 01/2020 - 11/2020 Bangalore, Karnataka **Tools:** (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, OneReach.ai, Dialog Flow)

- Worked on project like creating interactive chatbot for Unicomer Group, have also deployed chatbot in various form of channels (WhatsApp, RWC, Facebook, etc)
- Enhanced several features that reduced the manual intervention by automating the process which minimized the error rate by 80%
- Worked on maintaining a database containing feedback, conversations, and interests of individuals

PROJECTS

PlayerTracker: Building a Comprehensive Database for Tracking Player

02/2023 - 03/2023 Bangalore, Karnataka

Tools: Python, MySQL

- Created a python-interface, with a menu-driven to automate the process of admin users
- Collected and stored the duration using MySQL database and built 3
 triggers to streamline the process inserting data, and trigger to make
 decision on the subscription status
- Worked on Visualization palette to show the usage of the package and total hours played by the user using Matplotlib

HealthCare Management

01/2023 - 02/2023 Bangalore, Karnataka

Tools: Python, MySQL

- Developed over 15+ stored routines with features such as obtaining pharmacy information for particular medications, determining the count of patients treated for specific diseases in a given city and etc
- Utilized SQL Joins, Aggregate Functions, and Window Functions to extract meaningful insights from the data
- Constructed 3 triggers to monitor and store the date and time of when a new city or state is added to the database, and to track all transactions that involve updating inventory

EDUCATION

B.Tech - COM

Presidency University, Bengaluru 08/2018 - 07/2022 GPA 7.77 / 10

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python

MySQL



TECHNOLOGY SKILL SETS

Pandas

PySpark

NumPy

Hadoop

Hive

Unix Shell Scripting

Git

AWS

CERTIFICATION

Supervised Learning with scikit-learn

Datacamp, July 2020

Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python

Coursera, October 2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

1st Price- Photography Competition Secured 1st prize for On The Spot photography in an inter-college photography competition

INTERESTS

Editing, Traveling, Badminton